# RAMON HOYO

### FULLSTACK DEVELOPER



1

+58 412 6268761



rahoyo@outlook.com



Mérida, Venezuela



https://www.linkedin.com/in/rahoyo/



portfolio

## **PROFILE**

Hey! I'm Ramón Hoyo, a software developer with over 7 years of experience creating IT solutions that make a difference for users. I believe that building awesome solutions comes from loving what you do and putting in the hard work to stay competitive in a growing field. I know I've got more to learn, but I'm dedicated to improving every day!

## SKILLS

- Software Achirect
- Node Backend
- React Frontend
- Android native (kotlin)
- Basic GO developer
- Cloud (Docker, AWS, Heroku, Railway)
- CI/CD: Github actions
- More.

# **EDUCATION**

SYSTEM ENGINEER No completed

Universidad de Los Andes. only 4 se.mestres

2014 - 2016

## EXPERIENCE

#### **VINCI BLOCK**

Development Team Leader jun 2023 - may 2024

As the Development Team Lead, I was responsible for all IT solutions our team produced and successfully put in production.

One of the most common tasks I performed at Vinci Block was:

- Design at architectural level IT solutions that could integrate with existing modules from user stories.
- Control and audit commits and pull requests from other collaborators.
- Participate actively in the implementation of the solutions.
- Keep control of the overall infrastructure for the IT solutions.
- I participate in the frontend (React and React Native).

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

ADV Integradores y Consultores S.A. de C.V. (ADV IC)

2020 - 2023

- React Frontend Developer
- Node Backend Developer (vanilla node)
- Android Native Developer

# RAMON HOYO

### FULLSTACK DEVELOPER



+58 412 6268761

rahoyo@outlook.com

Mérida, Venezuela

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rahoyo/

# SOFT SKILLS

- Comunication
- Teamwork
- Problem Solving
- Adaptability
- Leadership
- Continuous Learning

#### **MULTI "ROLES" DEVELOPER**

ADVM Security Software C.A.

2017 - 2020

At ADVM Security, I had the opportunity to develop multiple solutions using different technologies according to the needs at that time.

- C++ Developer (RAD Studio, and Firemonkey)
- Android Native Developer (Kotlin)
- Desktop Apps (Electron, React and native c++ code).
- Other minor experiencies with other tools like, php, python.

#### **FREELANCER**

No place

2017 - now

On this time I also did some frenlancer proyects in my free time, one of those proyects were:

- Parking App "UPPITA". this was a react native app that I did for one client as its final career proyect.
- Feminicidios page. this was a React (next) page to show the femicides at México, this was presented as a final career proyect as well.
- Solving programming problem for students.

## IDIOMS

- Spanish Native
- English B1

As final words, I think I worth to mention that I have an strong foundation in data structures and algorithms underpins my approach to software development. I prioritize writing efficient and optimized code by employing appropriate data structures and algorithms, ensuring scalability and performance in applications. Whether it's implementing sorting algorithms, optimizing search operations, or designing data models, I consistently strive for elegant and efficient solutions that meet project requirements and exceed expectations.